Hi, Phil, how are you doing, I'm good, I'm good, a little bit tired, But yeah, I'm good.
Oh no why lots of housework this weekend.
We had to get the house ready.
So yeah, lots of do.
You said ready, ready for what.
Oh, we've got some people coming to visit.
So we had to we had to get ready for that.
Well, Phil, we are talking about housework today in real easy English.
So housework is all of those jobs you do in the house.
So cleaning washing, cooking, things like that.
Yep, all really.
Important things just before we start, I just wanted to remind everyone that they can go to our website to get a worksheet to get even more practice and that isbbclearningenglish.com. .
So Phil, you said at the weekend you did a lot of housework what did you do Well, I mean we we share out the housework,
But I was I had to make sure I was cleaning the kitchen I also did.
We say do the hoovering or do the vacuuming around all the carpets to make sure that's nice and clean under all the furniture so Gegie do you do a lot of housework?
Well, I live in a shared flat, so I have two housemates who are not super clean,
So I have a bit of a routine with them every weekend, one person will clean.
The communal areas, so those are the areas that are shared, so the kitchen and the living room,
One person will clean those properly so wipe the surfaces, wipe away the crumbs so the crumbs are little bits of food.
Then hoover or sweep the floor so that removes the crumbs from the floor so that the floor is ready to be mopped so when you mop that's when you make the floor wet
And properly clean that's a really impressive system.
I like the way you've already so organized we always find we run out of time to get a lot of housework done or we're doing stuff on the weekend or we're working during the week and so some of those jobs they get put
Off and put off and put off which isn't good but, Yeah, it happens sometimes well there's also just so many other things we would rather be doing so yeah it's
Easy to put off to delay Georgie, we're talking about household chores, is there one that you really?
Hate doing Yes, Phil, there is one job that comes to mind immediately, which is cleaning the bathroom specifically cleaning the toilet Oh yes, not very nice Yeah, no, not at all.
Do you have one that you hate the most I think what I really dislike is trying to clean things the bits on the cooker where everything gets stuck on and you have to really
Rub it and scrub it really hard.
I hate those jobs so do you you said that you share you share the the chores do you get your kids to do chores now that's a really good question we asked
The kids to do chores.
And sometimes they do something, okay, but not a lot, I'd really like them to be able to keep their rooms tidy that's never
Going to happen it feels.
I'd really like it if they could, you know, help out cleaning the living room, putting things away, but yeah, we haven't taught them very well, maybe one day, maybe.
It's when you become an adult I think that you really appreciate a clean space so hopefully that will come I was terrible as a teenager I didn't do much as a teenager at
All so this is just coming back to me now yeah.
Or me too so we've talked about chores that we hate doing, but are there any jobs that you enjoy doing Well, you know what, laundry or washing that's washing your clothes.
That can sometimes be really satisfying when you get a lot of it done and actually I've just got a new washing machine and it's much bigger than the one I had before so I can do so much
In one load.
Phil, that is so exciting even better because it's summer at the moment I can get it dry so quick it's it's amazing I love that putting a putting a load of washing
In the in the washing machine and then, Having it dry by the end of the day that is so good's it's the best thing teenage Georgie would be so disappointed that I'm excited
By laundry, but here we go.
Okay Phil, let's recap the vocabulary we used in this conversation starting with housework,
So this is the general term for jobs that we have to do.
In the house and then we had chores, which are the specific jobs that you have to do, for example, laundry.
Yes, so laundry is washing your clothes we say do the laundry or just do the washing Yes,
And we had some other chores, for example, hoovering and sweeping the floor, which is what you do when there are crumbs on the floor after you've swept the crumbs
You can mop the floor which is when you make the floor wet and clean it like that Yes, we also talked about jobs that you hate and sometimes when you really hate a job.
You end up putting it off that means to delay it if you put something off you delay something sometimes because you just don't want to do it So Phil that is the end of this episode
Of real easy English but we'll be back next week won't we Yes we'll be back with another episode Also don't forget about that worksheet that's on our websiteenglish.com. now bye.